Ernesto Crespo

Software Engineer

I'm a Software Engineer with more than +20 year of experience as a Python developer with Knowledge in Linux. I have experience developing API restful, working in data cleaning in Advanced Exploratory Data analysis, and working as AWS Cloud Engineer. I'm looking for a remote position as a Software Engineer focus in Data with Machine learning, and deep learning technologies in the health technology, EduTech, InsurTech, or Renewable Energy sectors.

EXPERIENCE

Asistensi Global Insurance, Inc, Software Engineer III— October 2021 - Present

- Reduce response times by fixing bugs and supporting services for the medical emergency management tool.
- Improve 60% of the medical prescription service for Asistensi clients in Mexico by designing and developing Medikit API integration with EMS.
- Enhance 50% (only backend for now) of Engineer software process in Emergency Management Systems EMS by developing Python Clean code validation.

Tech Stack: Django, Django-rest framework, PostgreSQL ,MongoDB, Docker, docker-compose, Serverless framework, Python, FastAPI, NestJS, Pandas, NumPy, Streamlit, Knime.

Talently Inc., Tech Coach — March 2023 - September 2023

As a Tech Coach, I helped several people improve their skills in Data Science, Data Engineering, and Big Data.
Tech Stack: AWS Athena, AWS RedShift, PostgreSQL, Python, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Big Data Analysis with PySpark.

Escala24x7, AWS Cloud Engineer — August 2019 - October 2021

- Improved by 80% the care attention by developing AWS APIs and automating the Escala customer service.
- Enhanced 90% of searches for bank customer calls by developing a Data lake for the call system of Banesco.
- Improved 80% of consults vehicle credit sales queries and customer delinquency by developing a Data lake parsing data from the vehicle monitoring system.

Tech Stack: Python, pandas, NumPy, S3, DynamoDB, RDS, lambda, cloud watch Event, SNS, SQS, AWS API, Step functions, cloud formation, AWS SAM, AWS Athena, AWS Glue, AWS Redshift.

Troc Global, BI Developer — July 2018 - August 2019

 Accelerated decision-making of the company's management by developing modules and APIs for EDA, PCA, and predictive analysis as a decision-making tool in the management of electronic and mobile equipment sales stores in Walmart establishments.

Tech Stack: Python, pandas, NumPy, sci-kit-learn, pyMC3, matplotlib, Seaborn, Django-rest framework, PostgreSQL, and rethinkDB.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Python; Intermediate: Golang Basic: R, Julia, javascript.

Frameworks Tools: <u>Advanced:</u> Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Bokeh, FastAPI, Streamlit; <u>Intermediate:</u> Scipy, PySpark, Scikit-learn, Django, Flask, ; <u>Basic:</u> Scrapy, Tensorflow, pyMC3, NLTK, Spacy, Pytest, Redis.

Data Base: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, MySQL, AWS RDS.

Tools: Tableu, Google Data Studio, Docker, Docker-compose, Knime, Slack, Linux.

Agile: Scrum, Extreme Programming.

Languages: Intermediate: English; Native: Spanish.

EDUCATION

University of Carabobo – Valencia, Electrical Engineer, December 2001.

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Scientist with Python Professional - Datacamp. November 2023. 116 hours.

Data scientist with Python – Datacamp. October 2023. 90 hours.

Big Data with PySpark - Datacamp. September 2023. 24 hours.

Machine Learning Fundamentals with Python - Datacamp. August 2023. 16 hours.

Natural Language Processing in Python - Datacamp. July 2023. 25 hours

Data Engineer – Datacamp. July 2023. 57 hours.

Data Analyst in SQL - Datacamp. March 2023. 39 hours.

Data Analyst with Python – Datacamp. January 2023. 36 hours.

More details → https://www.seraph.to/